ILGWU. Chicago Joint Board records 5780/044
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Chicago Joint Board records
1914-1975
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Chicago Joint Board
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/044
18.33 cubic feet
18.33 linear ft.
Correspondence, photographs.
Contains files on local unions throughout the Midwestern United States, as well as material on Joint Boards of Milwaukee, St. Louis, and Kansas City. In addition to meeting minutes of several local unions in Chicago (59, 74, 76, 100, 208, 212, 261, 314, 381), this subseries includes minutes of meetings relating to the Chicago Health Center and union health and retirement funds. General correspondence deals with organizing activities in the Midwest area. Subject files consist of correspondence concerning intra-office, union, and local matters, minutes of the Joint Board, and publications either created or collected by the Joint Board. Correspondents throughout both series include Morris Bialis, Abraham Plotkin, Harry Rufer and Harold Schwartz.
5490717
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 31, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 16, 2014
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Biographical / Historical
The cloak industry in Chicago has a very long history, beginning with the organization of the Chicago Cloak Makers' Union in 1889. In August 1914, The Cloak Operators' Local 44, the Cloak Cutters' Local 81, and the Cloak Pressers' Local 18 united to form the Chicago Joint Board. Shortly thereafter, the new Joint Board achieved a collective agreement with the manufacturers' association in 1915, and continued to increase organizing efforts and minimum wage scales. Work hours were reduced from 50 to 44 a week and by 1919, week work was instituted for the cloak industry. The dressmakers of the city formed Local 100 in 1915, won a collective agreement with a 40 hour week in 1919, and in 1920 joined the Chicago Joint Board. At the end of 1920, disputes between the Chicago Joint Board and the Cloak Manufacturers' Association occurred, and in December 1921 there was a five week strike which resulted in the abolishment of week-work abolished and return to the 48 hour work week. The dress trade had an eighteen week general strike in 1924. Soon though, the Joint Board began to make gains, first with the introduction of the 40 hour week in the cloak shops in 1928, and then the two week strike in August 1933 won a collective agreement and 35 hour week for the dressmakers.
Morris Bialis served as the manager for the Chicago Joint Board beginning in 1922, and Morris A. Goldstein served as his long time secretary-treasurer. In December 1939, the Chicago cloakmakers', one of the oldest groups in the ILGWU, celebrated their fiftieth anniversary, and the Chicago Joint Board celebrated 25 years. During the 1940s, the Joint Board consisted of five locals, Locals 5 (Cloak Operators), 18 (Cloak and Dress Pressers), 59 (Cloak Finishers), 81 (Cloak and Dress Cutters), and 100 (Dressmakers), the encompassed the cloak and silk dress trades. In 1946, the Joint Board purchased a six story building in the Loop to continue to be an instrumental player in labor and community affairs of Chicago.
The Chicago Health Center was opened in 1955, and in 1957, Bialis, who had also been appointed director of the Midwest Region in 1934, was aided by assistant director Harold Schwartz. At the end of the 1950s and beginning of the 1960s, the numbers of retirees increased the need for new workers to maintain payments of benefits in the face of a shrinking garment industry in Chicago. As the Chicago market continued to decline through the 1960s and union membership decreased, by 1974, Local 18 and 59 merged with Local 5, Local 54 merged with Local 76, and Local 208 and 212 merged with Local 261. After 54 years of service, Morris Bialis retired from his role as Joint Board manager in February 1976 (he had been elected an ILGWU vice-president in 1928). Harold Schwartz became the new manager of the Joint Board, as well as Midwest Region director, and Lou Montenegro named assistant director. In November 1978, Schwartz announced his retirement and assistant director Lou Montenegro was elected to succeed him as the regional manager as well as the manager of the Chicago Joint Board. As Chicago saw a rise in sweatshops during the 1980s, Montenegro led the Joint Board.
Scope and Contents
The records of the Chicago Joint Board are composed of two series: General Correspondence and Subject Files. These files not only provide information on the garment industry in the city of Chicago, but the correspondence and documents also present a picture of the smaller markets, such as rural Indiana and northern Michigan, including the small shops, manufacturers and local workers. The correspondence is arranged by city, many of which are within the Midwest Region that encompassed Chicago and the Joint Board. The records contain matters pertaining to shops in the smaller Midwest towns and include correspondence from organizers regarding shops and strikes, organizing campaigns, and often times resistance from employers and employees. Also well documented are the markets in bigger cities such as Decatur, Detroit, Grand Rapids, Indianapolis, and Peoria, and the records of the Milwaukee Joint Board (Locals 188, 273, 292, 322 and 334). Resistance to organizing in the shops of the small towns and rural areas is illustrated through union promotional material including flyers, leaflets, newsletters, and booklets extolling the virtues of joining the union.
The second component of the collection consists of subject files. The records include very early reports and correspondence; campaign to preserve Jane Addams Hull House; letters and photos from children "adopted" by the Joint Board that they financially supported after the war; hearings and case decisions that were brought before an impartial tribunal over disputes and complaints between the union, manufacturer associations (such as the Chicago Association of Dress Manufacturers), and individuals. Additionally, various departments within the national ILGWU structure that the Chicago Joint Board and its locals had business with are represented including the departments of auditing, research, political, management-engineering, education, and union label. Notable individuals in the series include Morris Bialis, David Dubinsky, Morris A. Goldstein (secretary-treasurer of the Chicago Joint Board), Frederick Umhey, Abraham Plotkin, Harold Schwartz (assistant director Midwest Department,1959-1966), and Louis Stulberg.
Of particular importance are the minutes of the Joint Board, beginning with 1914 which is in Yiddish, as well as the minutes of the various health and welfare funds, which also include reports agreements, and charters, by-laws. The subject files also provide documentation on the locals that comprised the Joint Board. There are Chicago Locals publications including, "The Needle," "Good News," which was published by the Educational Department of Locals 76 and 261, "Our Aim," the official organ of Local 91, and "Our Voice," published by the Chicago Joint Board.
The collection offers an interesting location to find information on the history of the Chicago area and garment industry, which are available in the reports submitted to "Justice." These provide summaries from Chicago and news from the Midwest Department, including updates on Michigan and Indiana. The collection also provides a status for the Chicago cloak and dress industry, as well as the Midwest, particularly useful through the reports submitted to the ILGWU General Executive Board.
There are also reports and correspondence from the Midwest Department, of which the Joint Board was a part of, but also see Midwest Region Records 5780/101.
Locals represented in the records of the Chicago Joint Board include: 67 (Toledo, OH),90 (Elgin, IL), 120 (Decatur, IL), 133 (Peoria, IL), 187 (Racine, WI), 189 (Batavia, IL), 238 (Gary, IN), 240 (Aurora, IL), 272 (Gilman, IL), 277 (Indianapolis, IN), 286 (Ishpeming, MI), 293 (Marquette and Negaunee), 317 (Bay City, MI), 328 (Kokomo, IN) 337 (Elkhart, IN), 354 (Alpena, MI), 355 (Clinton, IA), 355 (Manistee, MI), 364 (Port Huron, MI), 380 (Shelbyville, IN), 382 (Lincoln, IL), 392 (Logansport, IN), 441 (Kalamazoo, MI), 489 (Kendallville, IN), 508 (Mauston, WI).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/101: ILGWU. Mid-West Region records 5780/101 AV: ILGWU. Mid-West Region audio-visual materials
Women's clothing industry -- United States.; Labor unions -- United States -- Clothing workers.; Clothing workers -- United States.; Industrial relations -- United States.; Bialis, Morris.; Plotkin, Abraham.; Schwartz, Harold.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. -- Chicago Joint Board.
5490717
- Albion, Ill., 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Incl. corres. re Albion Mfg. Co.
- Alpena, Mich., Local 354, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  1937-Sept. 1940. I.c.w. and re. Alpena Garment Co., Inc.
- Alpena, Mich., Local 354, 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Oct. 1940-44.
- Anderson, Ind., local 361, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  1939-June 1940, Incl. corres. & printed material re Ward- Stelson Garment Co.
- Anderson, Ind., 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  July 1940-44.
- Anderson, Ind., 1939-1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Printed material.
- Appleton, Wisc., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Incl. corres. & printed material re Pox River Valley Knitting Co.
- Aurora, Ill., Local 240, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Incl. corres. re R. and M. Kaufman Co.
- Aurora, Ill., Local 240, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Aurora, Ill., Local 240, 1939-1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Batavia, Ill., Local 189, 1941-1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Bay City, Mich., Local 317, 1937-1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Incl. corres. & agreement re Wolverine Knitting Mills, Inc.
- Boston, Mass., 1936-1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Corres. w. Philip Kramer of Boston Cloak, Suit and Dressmakers Jt. Bd.
- Brazil, Ind., 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Incl. corres. re Brazil Mfg. Co.
- Brazil, Ind., 1938-1941 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Chattanooga, Tenn., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Chesterton, Ind., 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Incl. corres. re Forest City Mfg. Co.
- Chicago Heights, Ill., 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Cleveland, O., 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Incl. Cleveland Jt. Bd., corres. w. Abraham W. Katovsky, David Solomon, & H. D. Langer.
- Cleveland, O., 1940-1952 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Clinton, Iowa, Local 355, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Incl. corres. re Clinton Garment Co. (a subsidiary of Lee Garment Co. in Chicago, Ill.) & R. and M. Kaufman Co., hearing before NLRB; correspondents incl. Selma Buck & Beatrice Schonberg.
- Clinton, Iowa, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Incl. case of Nellie Howard & Louise Zimmerman, two employees discharged for union activities; i.c.w. A.E.Hubbard.
- Clinton, Iowa, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Clinton, Iowa, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Clinton, Iowa, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Dec. 1943-45.
- Covington, Ind., 1938 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Crawfordsville, Ind., Local 358, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Incl. corres re Decatur Garment Co.
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  1935 -Mar. 1936. I.c.w. Caroline Burke & re. A.F. Keating Co., Decatur Garment Co., Home Mfg. Co., & Osgood & Sons Mfg. Co.
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  April-Dec. 1936.
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Jan -Aug. 1937.
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Sept. -Dec. 1937.
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Jan-June 1938.
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  July-Dec. 1938.
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Jan-April 1940. I.c.w. Margaret Walpole, Helen Duncan & Inez Bennett.
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  May-June 1940.
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  July-Dec. 1940. Incl. corres. re Home Mfg. Co.
- Decatur, Ill. Local 120, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Jan -Aug. 1941.
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Sept-Dec. 1941.
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1942-1944 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1950-1955 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1956-1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  I.c.w. Margaret Songer.
- Decatur, Ill., Local 120, 1936-1940 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Radio broadcasts, A. Plotkin & Harry Rufer.
- Decatur, Ill., 1940 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Detroit, Mich., 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  1936-Aug. 1937. Incl. Muskegon & Grand Rapids, Mich. I.c.w. Michael Rosen.
- Detroit, Mich., 1937 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Sept-Dec. 1937.
- Detroit, Mich., 1938 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Jan-June 1938. I.c.w. Joseph Zuckerman & cases re Amazon Knitting Mills, Globe Knitting Works, Muskegon Garment Co. & Star Apron Mfg. Co.
- Detroit, Mich., 1938 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Detroit, Mich., 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Incl. corres. re Alpena Garment Co. & American Lady Corset Co.
- Detroit, Mich., 1941 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Detroit, Mich., 1943-1945 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  I.c.w. William E. Davis.
- Detroit, Mich., 1949-1951 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Detroit, Mich., 1954 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Detroit, Mich., 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Detroit, Mich., 1957-1962 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Dubuque, Iowa, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Incl. corres. re Dubuque Garment Co., Inc., & hearings before the NLRB.
- Elgin, Ill., Local 90, 1936-1945 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Elkhart, Ind., Local 337, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  I.c.w. Mary Engel.
- Elkhart, Ind., 1938-1945 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Escanaba, Mich., 1945 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Fairbury, Ill., 1937-1944 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Ft. Wayne, Ind., 1937-1944 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Garrett, Ind., 1941-1945 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  1955. Incl. corres. re Nature's Rival Co.
- Gary, Ind., Local 238, 1936-1941 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Incl. corres. re Gary Garment Co. & w. Eleanore Hoagland.
- Gilman, Ill., Local 272, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  I.c.w. Oliver Hartley re Western Dress Co.
- Grand Rapids, Mich., 1937 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Incl. corres. re Modern Globe Co.
- Grand Rapids, Mich., 1938-1955 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Huntington, Ind., Local 426, 1937-1955 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Huntington, W. Va., 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Illinois, Miscellaneous, 1936-1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Indiana, Miscellaneous, 1936-1944 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Indianapolis, Ind., Local 277, 1936-1937 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  1936-May 1937. I.c.w. Alice Burster re Real Silk Hosiery Mills, Inc.
- Indianapolis, Ind., 1937 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  June-Dec, 1937.
- Indianapolis, Ind., 1938 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Indianapolis, Ind., 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  1939-July 1940. Ind. corres. re Janalene, Inc.
- Indianapolis, Ind., 1940 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  Aug-Dec, 1940.
- Indianapolis, Ind., 1941-1943 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Indianapolis, Ind., 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Ishpeming, Mich., Local 286, 1941-1944 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  1941, Jan-June 1944 I.c.w. Ruby M. Dingman.
- Ishpeming, Mich., 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  July 1944-45.
- Ishpeming, Mich., 1955-1966 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  I.c.w. Ruth Craine.
- Jackson, Mich., 1937 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Incl. corres. re Trenton Garment Co.
- Kalamazoo, Mich., Local 441, 1936-1958 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Kansas City, Mo., 1935-1936 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Kendallville, Ind., Local 489, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Kenosha, Wisc., 1935 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Kokomo, Ind., Local 328, 1936-1939 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  I.c.w. Irish Austin re Reliance Mfg. Co., Sterling Division.
- Kokomo, Ind., 1941 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  I.c.w. Alida Cunningham.
- Kokomo, Ind., 1942-1943 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  1942 -June 1943.
- Kokomo, Ind., 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  July 1943-June 1944.
- Kokomo, Ind., 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Lacrosse, Wise., 1937 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  July-Sept, 1937. I.c.w. Alice Burster re Lacrosse Garment Co.
- Lacrosse, Wisc., 1937-1938 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Oct, 1937-38.
- LaPorte, Ind., 1936-1938 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  LaSalle, Ill.
- Lincoln, Ill., Local 382, 1937-1941 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Lincoln, Ill., 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  Corres. re Lincoln Allied Dress Co.
- Logansport, Ind., Local 392, 1939-1941 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  1939-Nov, 1941. Incl. corres. & strike material re H.W.Gossard Corset Co.
- Logansport, Ind., 1941-1942 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Dec, 1941-42.
- Logansport, Ind., 1943-1944 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Logansport, Ind., 1945-1957 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Los Angeles, Calif, 1936-1955 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  (Incl. L.A. Cloak & Dress Jt. Bds.) Incl. Isidor Stenzor memorandum to D. Dubinsky & Special GEB Committee on L. A. situation, Aug, 1955; publications. Shop News, 1941 & The Garmentator, 1944.
- Los Angeles, Calif., 1950 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  (L.A. Cloak & Dress Jt. Bds.) Corres., reports & printed material from & re Special Committee of the GEB (Charles S. Zimmerman, Morris Bialis & Meyer Perlstein) to correct the existing conditions (Communist situation) in the L.A. Cloak & Dress organizations.
- Los Angeles, Calif., 1956-1959 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  I.c.w. Isidor Stenzor & printed material from and re left- and rightwing groups of the affiliated locals in L.A.
- Manistee, Mich., Local 355, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Marinette, Wise., 1951-1960 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  Incl. corres. re Marinette Knitting Mills.
- Marquette and Negaunee, Mich., Local 293, 1941-1944 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  I.c.w. David M. Abilew of U.P. Dress Mfg. Co.
- Marquette and Negaunee, Mich., 1945-1955 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Mason City, Iowa, 1947-1953 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Mauston, Wisc., Local 508, 1963-1971 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Michigan, Miscellaneous, 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Milwaukee, Wisc., Local 188 and Milwaukee Joint Board, 1935-1940 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  I.c.w. Salvatore Ninfo & Benjamin Dolnick.
- Milwaukee, Wisc., 1941-1945 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Milwaukee, Wisc., Milwaukee Jt. Bd., 1948-1950 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  I.c.w. Harry P. Bovshow.
- Milwaukee, Wisc., Milwaukee Jt. Bd., 1951-1952 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Milwaukee, Wisc., Milwaukee Jt. Bd., 1953-1954 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Milwaukee, Wisc., Milwaukee Jt. Bd., 1955-1957 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Milwaukee, Wisc., Milwaukee Jt. Bd., 1958-1969 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Corres. w. George Paris.
- Milwaukee, Wisc., 1967-1971 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Minneapolis, Minn., 1936-1959 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  I.c.w. Michael Finkelstein, Twin Cities Jt. Bd.
- Mishawaka, Ind., 1936-1937 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- New Albany, Ind., 1937 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- New Albany, Ind., 1938 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Norway, Michigan, 1950-1958 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Incl. corres. & agreement w. Norway Needlecraft Corp.
- Peoria, Ill., Local 133, 1933-1936 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  I.c.w. Geraldine (Jerry) Hill.
- Peoria, Ill., 1937 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  Jan-May 1937. Incl. corres. re Betty Brown Co. & Chic Mfg. Co.
- Peoria, Ill., 1937 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  June-Nov, 1937.
- Peoria, Ill., 1938 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  Dec, 1937-Apr, 1938.
- Peoria, Ill., 1938-1939 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  May 1938- 1939.
- Peoria, Ill., 1940 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  Jan-May 1940.
- Peoria, Ill., 1940 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  June-Dec, 1940.
- Peoria, Ill, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  Jan-June 1941.
- Peoria, Ill., 1941 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  July-Dec, 1941.
- Peoria, Ill., 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Port Huron, Mich., Local 364, 1940-1941 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  1940-Mar. l941. I.c.w. Ruby M. Dingman re Erd-Marshall Co.
- Port Huron, Mich., 1941-1951 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  Apr- Dec, 1941, 1950-51.
- Puerto Rico, 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Racine, Wisc., Local 187, 1934-1957 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- St. Louis, Mo., St. Louis and Kansas City Joint Boards, 1933-1940 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  I.c.w. Meyer Perlstein.
- St. Louis, Mo., 1941-1945 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- St. Louis, Mo., 1947-1953 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- St. Louis, Mo., 1954-1957 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Shelbyville, Ind., Local 380, 1940-1945 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  Incl. corres. re Shelby Mfg. Co.
- South Bend, Ind., Local 366, 1936-1943 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  I.c.w. Blanche Cox & re Smoler Bros., Inc., Chicago, Ill.
- South Bend, Ind., 1944-1951 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Terre Haute, Ind., 1944-1945 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Toledo, Ohio, Local 67, 1951-1956 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Toronto, Canada, 1940-1949 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  1967. Incl. Toronto Jt. Bd.
- Warsaw, Ill., 1941-1945 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Watertown, Wisc, 1945-1962 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Wausau, Wisc., 1940-1944 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  Incl. corres. & agreement w. Marathon Rubber Products Co.
- Wisconsin, Miscellaneous. (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Zion City, Ill., 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Agreements, Independent and Collective, 1917-1947 (Box 16, Folder 7-9)
- Gen. Corres., 1917-1923 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  Correspondents incl. Meyer Perlstein & Morris Sigman.
- Gen. Corres., 1924-1925 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Gen. Corres., 1926-1930 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- General Reports, 1918-1923 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  Incl. reports of business agents, complaint department, & committee and related documents.
- General Reports, 1924-1926 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Addams Memorial, Jane, 1960-1965 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Adopted Children, 1951-1959 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  War orphans, sponsored through the Jewish Labor Committee.
- Aldrich and Aldrich, Inc., 1944 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- American Federation of Labor, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- American Financial and Development Corp. for Israel, 1951-1960 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Bialis, Morris and Abraham Plotkin, 1936-1941 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  Corres. bet. these two on all facets of Union activities.
- Bialis, Morris and Abraham Plotkin, 1942-1949 (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Bialis, Morris and Abraham Plotkin, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Bialis, Morris and Abraham Plotkin, 1952-1953 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Bialis, Morris, 1948-1949 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  European trip.
- Boris Smoler and Sons, Inc., 1935-1944 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Carsel, Wilfred, 1948-1949 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Cases, 1930-1957 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  Incl. Roth & Co. vs Chicago Jt. Bd., 1953; Federal Trade Commission vs Calif. Sportswear & Dress Assoc., et al.
- Chicago Cloak and Suit Mfrs. Assoc., 1951-1956 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Chicago Federation of Labor, 1950-1957 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Chicago Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, A History Of, by Wilfred Carsel, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  Acknowledgments, incl. Charles A. Beard.
- Chicago Sun; 1942-49. (Box 18, Folder 8)
- City of Hope (Los Angeles Sanatorium), 1937-1959 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Cloak and Dress Industry, Chicago, Fact Finding Committee, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Clothing Workers of America, Amalgamated, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Contributions, 1954-1971 (Box 18, Folder 12)